Guide to the Julius Edelstein papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series VII: Subject Files, 1917-1958 (1948-1953)
  - Indians
    - Bills (Box 119)
      - Seneca Indians, 1949-1950 (Box 119, Folder 2)
      - Ute Indians, 1951 (Box 119, Folder 3)
  - Interior, Department of the
    - General, 1950 (Box 119, Folder 4)
    - Appropriations, 1950 (Box 119, Folder 5)
    - Bridge Canyon, 1949-1950 (Box 119, Folder 6)
    - River and Harbors Bill, 1949-1950 (Box 119, Folder 7)
  - Labor
    - General, 1950-1952, (2 Folders) (Box 119, Folder 8-9)
    - Miami Hotel Strike, 1955 (Box 119, Folder 10)
    - Migratory, 1950-1952 (Box 119, Folder 11)
    - Taft-Hartley Act, 1947-1952 (Box 120, Folder 1)
  - Lehman, Herbert H.
    - Clippings and Commentary, 1950-1952, 1955-1956, (2 Folders) (Box 120, Folder 2-3)
    - Critical Articles and Editorials, 1950 (Box 120, Folder 4)
    - Voting Record, 1955 January 5-August 2 (Box 120, Folder 5)
  - Lobby Study
    - General, 1950 (Box 120, Folder 6)
    - McCarthyism--General, 1948, 1950, 1952-1954, (3 Folders) (Folder 7-9)
      - Attacks on Churches and Morality, 1953-1954 (Box 121, Folder 1)
      - Attacks on Individuals, 1950, 1953 (Box 121, Folder 2)
      - Attack on Philip Jessup, 1950 (Box 121, Folder 3)
      - Attacks on Press, 1950-1952, 1954 (Box 121, Folder 4)
      - Attacks on Senators, 1951-1954 (Box 121, Folder 5)
      - Attacks on State Department Individuals in Tydings Hearings, 1950 (Box 121, Folder 6)
      - Dispute with Dulles, 1953 (Box 121, Folder 7)
      - Encourages Government Employees to Violate Laws and Commit Espionage, 1954 (Box 121, Folder 8)
      - Foreign Press Comment, 1953 (Box 121, Folder 9)
      - Fort Monmouth, 1953-1954 (Box 121, Folder 10)
      - Malmedy Massacre Investigation, 1949 (Box 121, Folder 11)
      - Government Service Filled with Fear, 1954 (Box 121, Folder 12)
      - Engineering Projects, 1953-1954 (Box 121, Folder 13)
      - Foreign Operations Administration, 1953 (Box 121, Folder 14)
      - Lehman Charge Number 1 and 2, Undated, (2 Folders) (Box 121, Folder 15-16)
      - Overseas Libraries, 1953-1954 (Box 121, Folder 17)
      - Voice of America, 1953-1954 (Box 121, Folder 18)
    - Long Island Railroad, 1940, 1951 (Box 121, Folder 19)
  - Merchant Marine--General, 1950-1951, 1955-1956 (Box 121, Folder 20)
  - Mobilization
    - Armed Forces--General, 1950-1951, (3 Folders) (Box 121, Folder 21-23)
    - Armed Forces--General, 1950-1952, 1955, (7 Folders) (Box 122, Folder 1-7)
  - New York State Government--General, 1950-1956 (Box 122, Folder 8)
  - Politics--National
    - General, 1950-1952, 1955-1956, (3 Folders) (Box 123, Folder 1-3)
    - Korea, 1949-1951, (4 Folders) (Box 123, Folder 4-7)
    - Party Organization, 1955 (Box 123, Folder 8)
    - Truman, Harry S., 1951-1952 (Box 123, Folder 9)
  - Politics--New York
    - General, 1950-1956, (8 Folders) (Box 124, Folder 1-8)
    - New Creek, Staten Island, 1950 (Box 124, Folder 9)
  - Postal Legislation--General, 1950-1951, 1954, (2 Folders) (Box 124, Folder 10-11)
  - Power
    - General, 1946-1955, (2 Folders) (Box 125, Folder 1-2)
    - New York-New England Power Survey, 1949-1950 (Box 125, Folder 3)
    - New York Power Authority, 1951 (Box 125, Folder 4)
    - Niagara Falls (NY and Ont.)
      - General, 1950-1953, (2 Folders) (Box 125, Folder 5-6)
      - Background Material, 1931, 1950-1951 (Box 125, Folder 7)
      - Bills and Statements, 1950-1955 (Box 125, Folder 8)
      - Clippings, 1950-1951 (Box 126, Folder 1)
      - Correspondence, 1950-1956, (3 Folders) (Box 126, Folder 2-4)
      - Press Releases, 1950-1953 (Box 126, Folder 5)
      - Scenic Aspects--Includes Photographs, 1940, 1950 (Box 126, Folder 6)
      - Survey, 1951 (Box 126, Folder 7)
    - Public Utility Districts, 1950-1952 (Box 126, Folder 8)
    - Rural Electrification, 1950, 1953 (Box 127, Folder 1)
  - Railway Labor--General, 1950-1951, (2 Folders) (Box 127, Folder 2-3)
  - Reorganization of the Executive Branch
    - General, 1950-1952 (Box 127, Folder 4)
    - Citizen’s Committee for the Hoover Report, 1950-1951, (2 Folders) (Box 127, Folder 5-6)
  - Roads--General, 1950-1951, 1955 (Box 127, Folder 7)
  - Small Business-General, 1942, 1946, 1950-1953, (2 Folders) (Box 128, Folder 1-2)
  - Social Security
    - General, 1950-1951, 1956, (2 Folders) (Box 128, Folder 3-4)
    - Old Age and Survivors Insurance (OASI), 1950-1952 (Box 128, Folder 5)
    - Problems of Aging, 1947-1950 (Box 128, Folder 6)
    - Problems of the Aging, 1950 (Box 129, Folder 1)
    - Public Assistance Program, 1951 (Box 129, Folder 2)
    - Retirement, 1949-1950 (Box 129, Folder 3)
    - Unemployment Compensation, 1951-1952 (Box 129, Folder 4)
  - St. Lawrence Seaway
    - General, 1948-1952, (4 Folders) (Box 129, Folder 5-8)
    - Background Materials, 1951-1952, (2 Folders) (Box 130, Folder 1-2)
    - Connecting Channels, 1954-1955 (Box 130, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1947, 1949-1954, (3 Folders) (Box 130, Folder 4-6)
    - Government Agency Statements and Pamphlets, 1945, 1949-1951 (Box 130, Folder 7)
    - Government Agency Statements and Pamphlets, 1948, 1951-1952 (Box 131, Folder 1)
    - St. Lawrence Association--Statements, 1950-1952 (Box 131, Folder 2)
    - House Public Works Committee--Statements, 1950-1954, (2 Folders) (Box 131, Folder 3-4)
    - New York-New England Survey, 1949-1950, 1953 (Box 131, Folder 5)
    - Power Projects for Comparison, 1933, 1949-1951, (2 Folders) (Box 132, Folder 1-2)
    - Senate Foreign Relations Committee, 1952, (2 Folders) (Box 132, Folder 3-4)
    - Senate Public Works Committee, 1951 (Box 132, Folder 5)
    - Statements in Favor of Project, 1941, 1948-1950 (Box 132, Folder 6)
    - Statements in Favor of Project, 1948-1950 (Box 133, Folder 1)
    - State of New York Power Authority--Statements and Pamphlets, 1949-1952 ( 2 Folders) (Box 133, Folder 2-3)
  - Territories--United States
    - Alaska
      - Bills, 1950 (Box 133, Folder 4)
      - Eklutna Project, 1949-1950 (Box 133, Folder 5)
      - Rights of Natives, 1950-1951, 1953 (Box 133, Folder 6)
      - Statehood, 1950-1952 (Box 133, Folder 7)
      - Statehood, 1950-1952 (Box 134, Folder 1)
    - Hawaii-Statehood, 1937, 1949-1951 (Box 134, Folder 2)
    - Puerto Rico
      - General, 1949-1952, 1956 (Box 134, Folder 3)
      - Constitution, 1917, 1952 (Box 134, Folder 4)
    - Virgin Islands--General, 1946, 1950-1952 (Box 134, Folder 5)
  - Television--Federal Communications Commission, 1950-1952 (Box 134, Folder 6)
  - Tidelands (Offshore Oil Industry)--General, 1951-1953, 1955 (Box 134, Folder 7)
  - Vocational Rehabilitation--General, 1948-1951 (Box 134, Folder 8)
  - War Claims--General, 1950-1952 (Box 135, Folder 1)
  - Waterfront Commission Compact (NY and NJ)--General, 1953 (Box 135, Folder 2)
  - Welfare State--General, 1950-1952 (Box 135, Folder 3)
  - Natural Gas--General, 1956 (Box 135, Folder 4)
  - Additional Subject Files
    - American Jewish Committee and United Jewish Appeal, 1955-1956 (Box 135, Folder 5)
    - Roosevelt Memorial Commission--Correspondence, 1955-1958, (2 Folders) (Box 135, Folder 6-7)
    - Salk Vaccine, 1955 (Box 135, Folder 8)
    - Securities and Exchange Commission
      - Appointments, 1953-1955 (Box 135, Folder 9)
      - Proxy, 1953-1955 (Box 135, Folder 10)
- Series VIII: Address Index Cards, undated
  These records contain the names and addresses of individuals and organizations compiled by Edelstein. The materials are organized alphabetically with U through Z missing.
  - Aachen through Arnstein (Box 136)
  - Aron through Beavers (Box 137)
  - Bebee through Blanchard (Box 138)
  - Blanche through Brodsky (Box 139)
  - Brodt through Caputo (Box 140)
  - Carafas through Cocking (Box 141)
  - Cockrell through Crocker (Box 142)
  - Crowfoot through Derieux (Box 143)
  - Derigman through Ebmeyer (Box 144)
  - Ebner through Fena (Box 145)
  - Fendrick through Freeland (Box 146)
  - Freelander through Gil (Box 147)
  - Gilberg through Graf (Box 148)
  - Graff through Hess (Box 149)
  - Hesselbart through Hennessey (Box 150)
  - Hennig through Horne (Box 151)
  - Hornell through Jonathan (Box 152)
  - Jones through Kilga (Box 153)
  - Kilgore through Kzlowski (Box 154)
  - La through Levine, L. (Box 155)
  - Levine, M. through Lopresti (Box 156)
  - Loprima through Martin (Box 157)
  - Martina through McQuade (Box 158)
  - McQueen through Morrill (Box 159)
  - Morris through Nickols (Box 160)
  - Nicodemi through Pappageorge (Box 161)
  - Palombo through Plato (Box 162)
  - Platt through Seiger (Box 163)
  - Seik through Skutner (Box 164)
  - Skutnik through Stephens (Box 165)
  - Stephenson through Taxon (Box 166)
  - Taylor through Thines (Box 167)
- Series IX: 2009 Accession, 1952-1963
  These materials contain letters and memoranda, research files on immigration, the Democratic National Committee and policy papers by Joseph Rappaport. Also included are four photographs.
  - Chronological Files
    - 1960 July-1961 February, (9 Folders) (Box 170, Folder 1-9)
    - 1961 March-May (Box 171, Folder 1-7)
    - 1961 June-July (Box 172, Folder 1-4)
  - Personal Research Files
    - American Federation of Labor and Congress of Industrial Organizations, 1961 (Box 172, Folder 5)
    - Daily Notes--Includes Correspondence, 1960-1961, undated (Box 172, Folder 6)
  - Democratic National Committee--Nationalities Division
    - Activities of the Nationalities Division Democratic National Committee in the Election of President John Kennedy and Vice President Lyndon B. Johnson, 1960 (Box 172, Folder 7)
    - Captive Nations Week, 1962 (Box 172, Folder 8)
    - Chinese Section, 1962 (Box 172, Folder 9)
    - Congratulations, 1962 (Box 172, Folder 10)
    - Current (issues), 1962-1963 (Box 172, Folder 11)
    - Expense Report, 1962 (Box 172, Folder 12)
    - Expressions of Interest, 1962 (Box 172, Folder 13)
    - German Section, 1962 (Box 172, Folder 14)
    - Greek section, 1962 (Box 172, Folder 15)
    - Italian Section, 1962 (Box 172, Folder 16)
    - Leaders--General Correspondence, 1962 (Box 172, Folder 17)
    - Lists, undated (Box 172, Folder 18)
    - Meeting at the Mayflower Hotel, Washington, DC, 1962 June 13 (Box 172, Folder 19)
    - Report of the Nationalities Division Activities in the 1953 Elections, 1953 November 7 (Box 172, Folder 20)
    - Report of Activities of the Nationalities Division-Democratic National Committee and Plan of Action in the 1954 Congressional and Gubernatorial Elections, 1953 September 14-15 (Box 173, Folder 1)
    - Report of John T. R. Godlewski Nationalities Director Citizens for Kennedy-Johnson, 1960 (Box 173, Folder 2)
    - Report Polish -American Section Nationalities Division Democratic National Committee 1960 Presidential Election Campaign, 1960 (Box 173, Folder 3)
    - Report of Stanislaw Radziwill’s Appearances on Behalf of Senator John Kennedy During the Presidential Election Campaign of 1960 1960 November 15 (Box 173, Folder 4)
    - Statement of Chairman, 1963 (Box 173, Folder 5)
    - Suggested New Name for Division, 1962 (Box 173, Folder 6)
    - Ukrainian Section, 1962 (Box 173, Folder 7)
    - Program of Activities of the Nationalities Division in the 1952 Presidential and Congressional Elections, 1952 (Box 173, Folder 8)
    - Program of Activities of the Nationalities Division in the 1953 Municipal and County Elections, 1953 (Box 173, Folder 9)
    - Democratic State Convention Buffalo--Liberal Party Convention, 1958 (Box 173, Folder 10)
    - Immigration--Legislative Proposals, 1961 (Box 173, Folder 11)
    - United States Committee for Refugees, 1960-1961 (Box 173, Folder 12)
  - Photographs
    - Herbert H. Lehman with unidentified individuals (family portrait), undated (Box 173, Folder 13)
    - Herbert H. Lehman, Julius C. C. Edelstein and unidentified individuals at unidentified event, undated (Box 173, Folder 14)
    - Herbert and Edith Lehman, undated (Box 173, Folder 15)
    - Brien McMahon, Herbert H. Lehman, Julius Edelstein and unidentified individuals at unidentified event, undated (Box 173, Folder 16)